原创翻译  双语字幕
■
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.ZiMuZu.tv
改编自《冰与火之歌》
原著 乔治·R·R·马丁
第六季 第五集
权力的游戏
请进
Yes?
您的信  小姐
For you, my lady.
鼹鼠村离这里多远
How far is Mole's Town?
珊莎
Sansa.
布蕾妮小姐
Lady Brienne.
听闻你逃离临冬城  我担心得要死
When I heard you had escaped Winterfell, I feared the worst.
你不知道看到你安然无恙
You have no idea how happy I am
我有多高兴
to see you unharmed.
安然无恙
Unharmed?
你来干什么
What are you doing here?
我带谷地骑士北上前来救助你
I rode north with the Knights of the Vale to come to your aid.
他们此时正驻扎在卡林湾
They're encamped at Moat Cailin as we speak.
前来救助我
To come to my aid?
你之前知道拉姆斯为人吗
Did you know about Ramsay?
如果不知道  你就是白痴
If you didn't know, you're an idiot.
如果早就知道  你就是我的敌人
If you did know, you're my enemy.
想听听我们的新婚之夜是怎样的吗
Would you like to hear about our wedding night?
他从来不打我的脸
He never hurt my face.
他需要我的脸  奈德·史塔克女儿的脸
He needed my face, the face of Ned Stark's daughter.
可我身体的其他部分
But the rest of me,
其他部分  他为所欲为
he did what he liked with the rest of me
只要我还能给他一个继承人
as long as I could still give him an heir.
你认为他做了什么
What do you think he did?
我无法设想...
I can't begin to contemplate--
你认为他对我做了什么
What do you think he did to me?
珊莎小姐在问你问题
Lady Sansa asked you a question.
他打你
He beat you.
是的  他很喜欢打我
Yes, he enjoyed that.
你认为他还做了什么
What else do you think he did?
-珊莎  -还有什么
- Sansa, I-- - What else?
他用刀子割你了
Did he cut you?
-或许你一直都了解拉姆斯  -我不知道
- Maybe you did know about Ramsay all along. - I didn't know.
我以为你知道每个人的秘密
I thought you knew everyone's secrets.
我犯了错误  可怕的错误
I made a mistake, a horrible mistake.
我低估了一个陌生人
I underestimated a stranger.
他做的其他事情
The other things he did,
贵妇淑女不可宣之于口
ladies aren't supposed to talk about those things,
可我想妓院老板倒是常常挂在嘴边的
but I imagine brothel keepers talk about them all the time.
我现在还能感觉到
I can still feel it.
我说的不是我娇弱的内心还感到受伤
I don't mean in my tender heart it still pains me so.
我现在站在此处  身体上仍然有那样的感觉
I can still feel what he did in my body standing here right now.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
你说过你会保护我
You said you would protect me.
我会保护你  你一定要相信我  我会的
And I will. You must believe me when I tell you that I will.
我再也不信任你了  我也不再需要你
I don't believe you anymore. I don't need you anymore.
你保护不了我
You can't protect me.
假如我让布蕾妮砍了你
You won't even be able to protect yourself
你甚至不能保护自己
if I tell Brienne to cut you down.
我为何不让她砍了你
And why shouldn't I?
要我求你饶命吗
Do you want me to beg for my life?
如果你想要我求饶  我会的
If that's what you want, I will.
无论你有什么要求  只要我能做到
Whatever you ask that is in my power,
我都会去做
I will do.
要是我要你立刻死在这里呢
What if I want you to die here and now?
那我就去死
Then I will die.
你把我从谋害我家人的禽兽手里救出来
You freed me from the monsters who murdered my family
转送到另一伙谋害我家人的禽兽手里
and you gave me to other monsters who murdered my family.
回卡林湾去吧
Go back to Moat Cailin.
我哥哥和我会自己夺回北境
My brother and I will take back the North on our own.
我再也不要见到你
I never want to see you again.
若能消除你遭受的屈辱  我愿意做任何事
I would do anything to undo what's been done to you.
我知道我不能
I know that I can't.
在我离开前  能允许我再说一件事吗
Will you allow me to say one more thing before I go?
你的外叔公黑鱼布林登
Your great-uncle Brynden the Blackfish
已经集结徒利家的残余兵马  夺回了奔流城
has gathered what remains of the Tully forces and retaken Riverrun.
或许你该考虑与他取得联系
You might consider seeking him out.
有朝一日你可能会需要一支忠于你的军队
The time may come when you need an army loyal to you.
我有军队
I have an army.
你哥哥的军队
Your brother's army.
异母哥哥
Half-brother.
原创翻译  双语字幕
■
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.ZiMuZu.tv
翻译：Silmar 草草 潇湘月影
■
翻译：盐湖凉开水 ET外星人 泰斯
校对：泰斯·雪诺 Silmar   顾问：屈畅(ccxx)
时间轴：崽猪 加森 Avis aaaBao
后期：吉吉·波顿  总监：泰斯·雪诺
你还没准备好
You're not ready.
打开微信   扫描左侧二维码
或搜索公众号:    美剧炸了
了解最新影视资讯字幕信息
趁还来得及  赶紧回家吧
You should go home before it's too late.
你永远成不了我们的一员  史塔克小姐
You'll never be one of us, Lady Stark.
她说得有道理
She has a point.
第一代无面者中没有生来的贵族
None of the first Faceless Men were born to lords and ladies.
他们是瓦雷利亚矿井中的奴隶
They began as slaves in the mines of Valyria.
第一个无面者是谁
Who was the first?
他是无名之辈
He was no one.
千面之神教会他如何隐藏面孔
The Many-Faced God taught him how to shed his face
如何施与慈悲
and how to give the gift.
那个人又教给其他人  换取他们的侍奉
The man taught others in exchange for their service.
许多人侍奉  许多慈悲被施与
Many served, many more gifts were given.
很快奴隶主和监工都不在了
Soon all the masters and overseers were gone
无面者逃离了矿井
and the Faceless Men fled.
他们去了哪里
Where did they go?
这里
Here.
他们来到布拉佛斯的自由城邦建起这座房子
They founded the Free City of Braavos and built this house.
这些是他们生时的面孔
These were the faces they wore in life
在他们戴着其他面孔的时候
when they were not wearing others.
第一批无面者
The first Faceless Men.
现在女孩是他们中的一员了
And now a girl is one of them,
如果女孩想要
if a girl desires.
女孩什么都不想要
A girl has no desires.
谁
Who?
一个自称克莱恩夫人的女演员
An actress who calls herself Lady Crane.
在雪芭广场的剧院演出
She performs at the theater in Sheelba Square.
女孩得到了第二次机会
A girl has been given a second chance.
不会有第三次
There will not be a third.
无论怎样
One way or another,
千面厅都会多一张面孔
a face will be added to the hall.
哦  猎猪不成反被拱
Oh, murdered by a boar.
长毛畜生个头猛
The great big hairy whore.
獠牙一戳肠子流
He dug in his tusks and dug out my guts
我这就要完蛋喽
and soon I am no more.
快来  父亲  您得躺下
Oh, come, Father, in bed you must lie.
我爱您  父亲  请不要死
I love you, Father. Please don't die.
闭嘴  蠢猪  瑟曦  添酒
Shut up, you swine! Cersei, more wine.
我能感觉到冬日的寒风拂过大地
I feel the winds of winter as they lick across the land.
我们的儿子孤独地坐在冰冷的王座上
And our son alone on that cold, cold throne
无人教导
without a guiding hand.
谁来教他坚强  谁来教他威仪
Who will teach him strength? Who will teach him grace?
当他要学会直面黑暗时
To whom will he turn when it's time
又该向谁求助
to learn to look darkness in the face?
奈德·史塔克就行  再给我拿些酒来
Ned Stark will do fine. Now bring me more wine.
这是怎么回事
Ooh, what's happened here, then?
他叫你来  奈德·史塔克
He brought you here, Ned Stark,
是因为你是天下最聪明的人
'cause you're the brightest fellow in the land.
你应该当我们的国王
You should be king of us all
我该做你的首相
and I should be your Hand.
我们北境的汉子最会管教
We men of the North are right good hands
人民守法了
at keeping people lawful.
我想征求他的同意
I'd ask him for permission,
但他太臭了
but he smells too bloody awful.
我死了  我死了
I die! I die!
我得躺在这里了
And here I now must lie.
哎呀  糟糕
Oh, woe. Oh, no.
我要死了
Oh, I am about to go.
你可以做乔佛里的首相吗
Will you stay on as Joffrey's Hand?
我要的是铁王座
The Iron Throne's what I demand.
-你不能  -我可以
- You cannot. - I can.
-你不会的  -我会的
- You will not. - I will.
-你不敢  -我敢
- You dare not. - I dare yes.
-但是继承顺序  -那是什么意思
- The line of succession. - What's that mean?
-正当程序  -那是什么意思
- The proper progression. - What's that mean?
-合法晋升  -那是什么意思
- The lawful ascension. - What's that mean?
闪开吧  把椅子给我
So move along, give me my chair
就不会再有麻烦了
and there won't be no more trouble.
但我们都说好的
But we had a deal all done and dusted.
我开始觉得你不值得信任了
I'm starting to think you can't be trusted.
救救我父亲
Save my father.
你的确该饶他一命  杀了他对你没有好处
Truly you should. Killing the man will do you no good.
-救救他吧  -饶他一命
- Save him, please. - Show him mercy.
让人民看到一个好国王的气度
Show the people what a good king should be.
各位  别紧张
Good people, you may all relax.
我父亲的朋友会被饶恕
My father's friend shall be spared the--
父亲  不
Father! No!
父亲
Oh, Father.
别担心  没事的
Worry not! All is well.
我有我父亲泰温·兰尼斯特下达的法令
I have here a decree from my father Tywin Lannister,
他是世上最有钱的人
the richest man you'll see.
他宣布我为国王之手
He proclaims me Hand of the King.
这位子永远属于我了
The position's mine for life.
他还允许我娶珊莎为妻
And he's given me permission to take Sansa as my wife.
你会发现我个头虽然不高
You'll learn that what I lack in height,
胃口却大得很
I make up for in appetite.
忘了你的誓约吧
So let's forget about your plight,
去彩排我们的新婚之夜
and go rehearse our wedding night.
有个疣子  有两个
It's a wart. Two warts.
我的命根子上有俩疣子
I've got two fucking warts on my cock.
别担心  亲爱的
Well, don't worry, love.
过个五六年就消了
They usually go away in five or six years.
把这件洗了  沾了我一身臭气
Oh, wash this, darling. It stinks of me.
你可以演得更好的  比安卡  亲爱的
You can do better, Bianca, dear.
你必须演得更好
You must do.
我就两句台词
I had two lines.
没有所谓的小角色  你太浮夸了
There are no small parts. You rang very false.
我浮夸
I rang very false?
亲爱的  你需要有人给你点真实感
What you need, love, is for someone to ring you true.
你昨晚可没抱怨我
You weren't complaining about me last night.
需要我给您拿点红酒来吗  克连恩夫人
May I get you some wine, Lady Crane?
我喜欢喝朗姆酒  博邦奴
I'm a rum girl, Bobono.
如果我们要亲近  你就得知道这些事
You need to know that if we're going to be intimate.
我们当然会亲近了
Of course we're going to be intimate.
迟早的事
It's only a matter of time.
敬我们的孩子们
To our children.
原他们有你的才华
May they have your talent.
和你的下流
And your filthy mind.
女孩要在朗姆酒里下毒
A girl will poison the rum.
只有克连恩夫人喝那个
Lady Crane is the only one who drinks it.
如果女孩可以用大厅里的脸
If a girl could use one of the faces from the hall...
女孩还没准备好
A girl is not ready.
她是个好演员
She's a good actress.
某人听说了
So a man has heard.
似乎是个好人
Seems like a decent woman.
难道死亡只带走恶人而留下好人吗
Does death only come for the wicked and leave the decent behind?
不
No.
谁要她死
Who wants her dead?
无所谓  钱已付
That does not matter. The price was paid.
年轻一点的那个女演员
The younger actress.
她嫉妒克连恩夫人演得更好
She's jealous because Lady Crane is better.
女孩得决定她是否想服侍千面之神
A girl must decide if she wants to serve the Many-Faced God.
女孩已经决定了
A girl has decided.
仆人不提问题
A servant does not ask questions.
不不不
No! No! No!
是你
It was you.
是你创造了异鬼
You made the white walkers.
我们当时在打仗
We were at war.
我们惨遭屠戮
We were being slaughtered.
我们的圣树被砍伐
Our sacred trees cut down.
我们需要保护自己
We needed to defend ourselves.
抵御谁
From whom?
你们
From you.
人类
From men.
淹神为证
We speak in the presence of the Drowned God.
我们今天以他之名齐聚于此
In his name we gather today
选一位新王做我们的领袖
to choose a new king as our leader.
谁要称王
Who makes a claim?
我是雅拉·葛雷乔伊
I am Yara Greyjoy,
巴隆·葛雷乔伊之女
daughter of Balon Greyjoy,
他是铁群岛的先王
King of the Iron Islands.
我要继承盐王座
I claim the Salt Throne.
我们从没有过女王  一个也没有
We've never had a queen. Not once.
我们有好多没做过的事呢
There are many things we've never done.
我们也从未在这世上闯出过名堂
We've never made our mark upon the world.
维斯特洛的大老爷们根本不在意我们
The great lords of Westeros pay us no mind
直到我们在他们的王国不断地烧杀掳掠
until our little raids buzz through their kingdoms
成了他们的眼中钉肉中刺
long enough to become a nuisance.
然后他们将我们打垮
Then they swat us down.
征服我们  羞辱我们
They conquer us, humiliate us,
又忘记我们的存在
and go right back to forgetting we exist.
没错
Aye!
-我们是海洋的子民  -没错
- We are a sea people. - Aye!
-我们的神是海洋的神灵  -没错
- Our god is a sea god. - Aye!
当我成为女王  我们将打造一支舰队...
When I am queen, we will build a fleet that--
-你不能做女王  -我还没有说完
- You shall not be queen! - I am not finished!
你说完了  女人不能领导我们
Yes, you are! A woman will not lead us.
毕竟巴隆的儿子已经回来了
Not when Balon's own male heir has returned.
我是席恩·葛雷乔伊
I am Theon Greyjoy...
巴隆·葛雷乔伊仅存的儿子
last living son of Balon Greyjoy.
她是你们合法的统治者
And she is your rightful ruler.
没错
Aye!
你们曾在她的号令下出海
Those of you that have sailed under her,
在场的很多人
and there are many of you here,
-也都了解她  -没错
- you know what she is. - Aye!
-她是掠夺者  -没错
- She is a reaver. - Aye!
-她是战士  -没错
- She is a warrior. - Aye!
她是铁种
She is ironborn!
没错
Aye!
没有比她更合适的领袖
We will find no better leader.
她就是我们的女王
This is our queen.
雅拉  雅拉  雅拉
Yara! Yara! Yara!
我是攸伦·葛雷乔伊
I'm Euron Greyjoy.
我要继承盐王座
I claim the Salt Throne.
侄女
Niece.
侄子
Nephew.
小席恩
Little Theon.
听说你把事情搞砸了
Heard you managed to fuck things right into the ground.
夺下一座守不住的城堡
Captured a castle you couldn't keep.
害自己沦为阶下囚
Got yourself taken prisoner.
还听说你没了命根子
Even heard you have no cock.
难怪你觉得女人可以称王
Explains why you think a woman can be king.
你什么时候回来的  叔叔
When did you return, Uncle?
几天前
A few days ago.
我有一些事情需要处理
I had some things to take care of.
拖了很久了
Long overdue.
很高兴你来了
I'm glad you're here.
现在我知道登基后首先该做什么
Now I know what my first act as queen will be.
处死杀害我父亲的凶手
To execute the man who killed my father.
没错
I did.
是我杀了他
I killed him.
把他扔下了索桥
Threw him right over a rope bridge
看着他摔死
and watched him fall.
他在领导我们走向末路
He was leading us nowhere
若不是我  我们还在死路上呢
and we would still be heading there if it weren't for me.
没人爱戴他  没人想要追随他
No one loved him. No one wanted to follow him.
他害我们卷进了两场赢不了的战争
He led us into two wars we couldn't win.
我向各位道歉  没有早几年杀了他
I apologize to you all for not killing him years ago.
那恐怕很难
That would have been hard to do.
你不在这里
You weren't here.
上次听到你的消息  你正在满世界闲逛
Last I heard, you were gallivanting around the world
纵情享乐
having a grand old time.
闲逛
Gallivanting?
你的命根子被切掉以后
That the sort of thing you start to say
开始这么说话了吗
once your dick gets chopped off?
是维斯特洛的老爷们教你这么说话吗
Did the great lords of Westeros teach you words like that?
你当时走了
You were gone.
雅拉在
Yara was here.
身为铁种  领导铁种
Being ironborn. Leading ironborn.
准备着带领我们重拾荣光
Getting ready to bring us back to glory.
她打算怎么做
And how will she do that?
我会打造一支世上最大的舰队
I will build the largest fleet the world has ever seen.
想法对头
Right idea,
只不过打造铁舰队的人将会是我
except I'm the one who's going to build the Iron Fleet
因为只有我知道如何使用它
because I'm the one who knows how to use it.
我曾周游世界
I've been all over the world.
我比在场所有人都要见多识广
I've seen more of it than all of you combined.
在大海对岸  有一个人
And across the sea there is a person
跟我们一样憎恨维斯特洛的老爷们
who hates the great lords of Westeros just as much as we do.
那人有一支大军
Someone with a large army,
三只巨龙  眼下尚无夫婿
three large dragons, and no husband.
我会打造一支舰队
I'm going to build that fleet
闲逛过去
and I'm going to gallivant right over
将它交给丹妮莉丝·坦格利安
and give it to Daenerys Targaryen
再奉上我的大屌
along with my big cock.
你要勾引龙女王
You're going to seduce the Dragon Queen?
我不会勾引她  勾引她的是铁舰队
I'm not going to seduce her. The Iron Fleet will seduce her.
我们将一起征服七国
And together we're going to take the Seven Kingdoms.
我并非生来就是王
I wasn't born to be king.
我付了铁钱
I paid the iron price
现在我站在这里
and here I stand.
攸伦  攸伦  攸伦  攸伦
Euron! Euron! Euron! Euron!
攸伦  攸伦
Euron! Euron!
让攸伦  您的仆人
May Euron, your servant,
与您一样从海里重生
be born again from the sea as you were.
赐予他海盐的祝福  赐予他坚石的祝福
Bless him with salt. Bless him with stone.
赐予他钢铁的祝福
Bless him with steel.
听那海涛的声音  听那神灵的呼唤
Listen to the waves. Listen to the god.
他正在对我们说话  他说
He is speaking to us and he says
我们将奉攸伦·葛雷乔伊为王
we shall have no king but Euron Greyjoy.
让大海洗去你的愚昧和虚妄
Let the sea wash your follies and your vanities away.
淹死过去的攸伦
Let the old Euron drown.
让海水充盈他的肺
Let his lungs fill with seawater.
让鱼儿吃掉他眼睛上的鳞
Let the fish eat the scales off his eyes.
逝者不死
What is dead may never die,
必将再起  其势更烈
but rises again harder and stronger.
逝者不死
What is dead may never die.
我的侄儿侄女在哪儿
Where are my niece and nephew?
我们去杀了他们
Let's go murder them.
他们偷走了我们最好的船
They stole our best ships.
那也救不了他们
Won't be enough to save them.
回家去
Go back to your homes.
砍倒每一棵树
Chop down every tree you can find.
锯开木头  开始造船
Quarter-saw the timber and start building.
我要每一个男人都去加工木板
I want every man bending planks.
我要每一个女人都去编织船帆
I want every woman spinning flax for sails.
为我造千艘战舰
Build me a thousand ships
我将还你们整个世界
and I will give you this world.
我两次将你放逐
I banished you twice.
你又两度回到我身边
You came back twice.
你还救了我的命
And you saved my life.
所以我既不能接受你
So I can't take you back
也不能把你赶走
and I can't send you away.
您必须把我赶走
You must send me away.
有解药吗
Is there a cure?
我不清楚
I don't know.
你还剩多长时间
How long does it take?
这个我也不清楚
I don't know that either.
但是我见过病况更严重的样子
But I've seen what happens when it goes far enough.
在那之前我会做个了断
I'll end things before that.
我很遗憾
I'm sorry.
我非常遗憾
I'm so sorry.
不用这样
Don't be.
侍奉您是我毕生的愿望
All I've ever wanted was to serve you.
提利昂·兰尼斯特说的没错
Tyrion Lannister was right.
我爱您
I love you.
永远爱您
I'll always love you.
别了  卡丽熙
Good-bye, Khaleesi.
别离开你的女王
Do not walk away from your queen,
安达尔人乔拉
Jorah the Andal.
我还没允许你退下
You have not been dismissed.
你曾宣誓效忠于我
You pledged yourself to me.
你发誓终生奉行我的意旨
You swore to obey my commands for the rest of your life.
现在  我命令你找到解药
Well, I command you to find the cure
无论它在天涯海角
wherever it is in this world.
我命令你治愈自己
I command you to heal yourself
然后回到我身边
and then return to me.
当我夺取七大王国时
When I take the Seven Kingdoms,
我要你伴我左右
I need you by my side.
在我们与奴隶主达成协议之后的两个星期内
In the last fortnight since our pact with the Masters,
鹰身女妖之子造成了多少伤亡
how many killings have been carried out by the Sons of the Harpy?
无人伤亡
None.
自由人又杀了多少奴隶主呢
And how many Masters have been butchered by the free men?
两个  但那是达成协议当天的事情
Two, but that was the day of the pact.
在那之后  什么都没发生
Since then, nothing.
所以可以说我们维持了脆弱的和平
So it's safe to say that a fragile peace has taken hold.
暂时的和平
For now.
暂时的和平已经是我们得到的最好结果了
For now is the best we get in our profession.
然而这并不足够
It's not enough.
考虑到这座城市曾处于内战边缘
Considering the city was on the brink of civil war,
我觉得这是个不错的开头
I'd say it's a good start.
弥林只有和平可不够
It's not enough for Meereen to have peace.
他们得知道和平是丹妮莉丝带来的
They need to know Daenerys is responsible for it.
鹰身女妖之子有一套不错的说法
The Sons of the Harpy have a good story.
反抗异邦入侵者
Resist the foreign invaders.
我们的女王有一套更好的说法
Our queen has an even better story.
龙之母  解放者  以及所有那些名号
Mother of Dragons, Breaker of Chains and all that.
最新美剧下载
www.ZiMuZu.tv
人民知道是谁带来了自由
The people know who brought them freedom.
是的  但他们知道是谁提供了安全吗
Yes, but do they know who brought them security?
是谁终结了暴力
Who brought about an end to the violence?
我们需要一个人民信任的人
We need someone the people trust,
那种他们相信不会被收买或利用的人
someone they know cannot be bought or influenced.
听起来是个英雄人物  我们去哪里找他呢
Sounds like quite the hero. Where would we find him?
谁说是"他"了
Who said anything about "Him"?
在诸位面前的是金瓦拉
瓦兰提斯红神庙的大祭司
真相之焰
智慧之光
光之王的第一仆人
欢迎来到弥林
我就会说这几句瓦雷利亚语
That's about the extent of my Valyrian.
感谢你不远万里地来到这里
Thank you for travelling all this way.
我亲身体验过旅途的艰辛
I know from personal experience how uncomfortable the journey can be.
其实我们需要你的帮助
The truth is we need your help.
我们希望能够说服你...
We had hoped that we could somehow persuade you to--
你们不需要说服我
You don't need to persuade me.
我就是来提供帮助的
I came to help.
风暴降生丹妮莉丝是预言之人
Daenerys Stormborn is the one who was promised.
她从烈火中重生  再造这个世界
From the fire she was reborn to remake the world.
没错
Yes.
她解开了奴隶们身上的锁链
She has freed the slaves from their chains
钉死了罪恶万端的奴隶主
and crucified the Masters for their sins.
她确实做了
She did indeed.
她的龙拥有火焰铸就的血肉
Her dragons are fire made flesh,
那是光之王的馈赠
a gift from the Lord of Light.
但是这些你们以前都听过  不是吗
But you heard all of this before, haven't you?
在瓦兰提斯的长桥上
On the Long Bridge of Volantis.
龙将净化无数不信真主之人
The dragons will purify nonbelievers by the thousands,
让他们的罪恶与血肉灰飞烟灭
burning their sins and flesh away.
我们最好不要净化太多这种人
Ideally we'd avoid purifying too many nonbelievers.
龙之母有许多不同信仰的追随者
The Mother of Dragons has followers of many different faiths.
你希望女王受到景仰和服从
You want your queen to be worshipped and obeyed.
而当她不在的时候  你希望她的顾问们
And while she's gone, you want her advisors
也受到景仰和服从
to be worshipped and obeyed.
服从就行了
I'd settle for obeyed.
我会召集最雄辩的祭司们
I will summon my most eloquent priests.
让他们散布消息
They will spread the word.
说丹妮莉丝是被派来带领人民
Daenerys has been sent to lead the people against the darkness
在现在与将来的大战中对抗黑暗的人
in this war and in the great war still to come.
听起来棒极了
That sounds most excellent.
一个叫做史坦尼斯·拜拉席恩的人
A man named Stannis Baratheon was anointed
曾被你们的一位祭司认定为神选之人
as the chosen one by one of your priestesses.
他也有过不可限量的前途
He, too, had a glorious destiny.
他曾经攻打君临  被我身边的人
He attacked King's Landing and was soundly defeated
打得大败而归
by the man standing beside me.
听说最近他又被打败了
Last I had heard, he had been defeated again,
这次是在临冬城  再也不能卷土重来
this time at Winterfell and this time for good.
我们将非常感激
We'd be most grateful for
你对女王提供的一切支持
any support you could provide the queen.
我认为让狂热的信徒承认错误不是件容易的事
I suppose it's hard for a fanatic to admit a mistake.
那不就是身为狂热信徒的全部意义吗
Isn't that the whole point of being a fanatic?
你们永远是正确的
You're always right.
一切皆为光之王的旨意
Everything is the Lord's will.
但凡人会犯错
But men and women make mistakes.
即使是真主忠诚的仆人
Even honest servants of the Lord.
而你  真主忠诚的仆人
And you, an honest servant of the Lord,
我为什么要相信你知道的
why should I trust you to know any more
比辅佐史坦尼斯的女祭司多
than the priestess who counseled Stannis?
我的朋友对宗教抱有善意的怀疑
My friend has a healthy skepticism of religion,
但我们都是女王的忠实支持者
but we are all loyal supporters of the queen.
任何人的所属所在皆有缘由
Everyone is what they are and where they are for a reason.
发生可怕的事情亦有缘由
Terrible things happen for a reason.
就拿你小时候的遭遇来说吧  瓦里斯大人
Take what happened to you, Lord Varys, when you were a child.
若你不曾受到二流男巫的摧残
If not for your mutilation at the hand of a second-rate sorcerer,
你就无法在此处辅佐天命之人
you wouldn't be here helping the Lord's Chosen
将真主的光明带到世上
bring his light into the world.
知识让你强大
Knowledge has made you powerful.
但你不知道的还有很多
But there's still so much you don't know.
你还记得那天晚上  男巫把你的命根子
Do you remember what you heard that night
丢进火里时  你听到了什么吗
when the sorcerer tossed your parts in the fire?
你听见了从火焰中传出的声音  还记得吗
You heard a voice call out from the flames. Do you remember?
要我告诉你那声音说了什么吗
Should I tell you what the voice said?
要我告诉你说话者的名号吗
Should I tell you the name of the one who spoke?
我们为同一个女王效力
We serve the same queen.
如果你是她真正的朋友
If you are her true friend,
你就无需害怕我
you have nothing to fear from me.
夜王  他看见我了
He saw me, the Night King!
-他看见我了  -他碰到你了
- He saw me! - He touched you.
我不知道  他离我很近  但是...
I don't know. He was close, but...
他碰到你了
He touched you.
他知道你在这里  他会来找你
He knows you are here. He'll come for you.
但他无法进来
But he can't get in.
他现在可以了  你身上有他的印记
He can now. His mark is on you.
你们必须离开  所有人
You must leave, all of you.
快  阿多  帮我搬雪橇
Come on, Hodor. Help me with the sledge.
阿多
Hodor.
对不起  我不是有意的
I'm sorry. I didn't mean to.
-是时候了  -是时候做什么
- The time has come. - The time for what?
让你成为我
For you to become me.
但我准备好了吗
But am I ready?
没有
No.
我们无法抵御北边的异鬼
We can't defend the north from the walkers
同时抵御南边的波顿家族
and the south from the Boltons.
如果我们要存活下来  我们就需要临冬城
If we want to survive, we need Winterfell
而要攻下临冬城  我们需要更多兵力
and to take Winterfell, we need more men.
除了史塔克家和波顿家
Aside from the Starks and the Boltons,
北境最强大的家族
the most powerful houses in the North
是安柏家  卡史塔克家和曼德勒家
are the Umbers, the Karstarks, and the Manderlys.
安柏家和卡史塔克家
The Umbers and the Karstarks
已经公开效忠波顿家
have already declared for the Boltons,
所以我们目前形势严峻
so we're not doing so well there.
安柏家把瑞肯交给了我们的敌人  该吊死他们
The Umbers gave Rickon to our enemies. They can hang.
但卡史塔克家效忠拉姆斯
But the Karstarks declared for Ramsay
是因为他们不知道还有别的选择
without knowing they had another choice.
不好意思  小姐
I beg your pardon, my lady,
但他们知道史塔克家的人杀了他们父亲
but they know that a Stark beheaded their father.
我不认为我们可以指望他们
I don't think we can count on them either.
你有多了解北境  戴佛斯爵士
How well do you know the North, Ser Davos?
少之又少  小姐
Precious little, my lady.
我父亲总说北境人是不一样的
My father always said Northerners are different.
更忠诚  对外人更有戒心
More loyal, more suspicious of outsiders.
他们可能是忠诚
They may well be loyal,
但当波顿背叛你的家族时
but how many rose up against the Boltons
他们又有多少人站出来了
when they betrayed your family?
我也许不了解北境  但我了解人
I may not know the North, but I know men.
无论来自何处  他们都或多或少地相似
They're more or less the same in any corner of the world
即使他们中最勇敢的人也不愿意看到
and even the bravest of them don't want to see
自己的妻儿因注定的失败而被剥皮
their wives and children skinned for a lost cause.
如果琼恩要说服他们并肩作战
If Jon's going to convince them to fight alongside him,
他们得相信自己能够胜利
they need to believe it's a fight they can win.
北境的家族不止这三个
There are more than three other houses in the North...
葛洛佛  莫尔蒙  赛文
Glover, Mormont, Cerwyn,
麦辛  霍伍德
Mazin, Hornwood.
二十几个  他们一起足以与其他家族抗衡
Two dozen more. Together they equal all the others.
我们可以一点一点地争取
We can start small and build.
北境永不遗忘
The North remembers.
他们记得史塔克的名字
They remember the Stark name.
人们会为此不惜一切代价
People will still risk everything for it,
从白港到拉姆斯自家门前
from White Harbor to Ramsay's own door.
我不怀疑
I don't doubt it.
但琼恩没有继承史塔克的姓
But Jon doesn't have the Stark name.
他没有  但我有
No, but I do.
琼恩是奈德·史塔克的儿子
Jon is every bit as much Ned Stark's son
就像拉姆斯是卢斯·波顿的儿子
as Ramsay is Roose Bolton's.
而且还有徒利家  虽然他们不是北境人
And there are also the Tullys. They're not Northern,
但他们会毫不犹疑地援助我们对抗波顿家
but they will back us against the Boltons without question.
我不知道徒利家还有军队
I didn't know the Tullys still had an army.
我外叔公黑鱼重建了军队  并夺回了奔流城
My uncle the Blackfish has reformed it and retaken Riverrun.
你是怎么知道的
How do you know that?
在我逃离临冬城之前  拉姆斯收到了信
Ramsay received a raven before I escaped Winterfell.
那很好
That's good.
黑鱼是个传奇人物
The Blackfish is a legend.
他的支持意义重大
His support would mean a great deal.
史塔克  徒利  再加上一些家族
Stark, Tully, a few more houses,
有那么一点儿胜利的曙光了
almost starts to look like a winning side.
我发过誓要保护你  小姐
I've sworn to protect you, my lady.
你听到他们说的了  我们需要更多兵力
You heard them. We need more men
而我外叔公有一支军队
and my uncle has an army.
我们可以给黑鱼送信
We can send the Blackfish a raven.
万一被拉姆斯拦截怎么办
Can't risk Ramsay intercepting it.
只能你亲自送
It has to be you.
去奔流城  我叔叔会接待你的
Ride for Riverrun. My uncle will talk to you
你也知道该怎么跟他说
and you'll know how to talk to him.
怎么了
What is it?
我不想把你一个人留下
I don't like leaving you here alone.
因为琼恩
With Jon?
不是他  他看起来很可靠
Not him. He seems trustworthy.
也许有点阴沉
A bit brooding, perhaps.
我想这也可以理解
I suppose that's understandable, considering.
其他人就另说了
The others, though.
戴佛斯和红袍女协助他人谋杀其亲弟弟
Davos and the Red Woman helped a man murder his own brother
使用血魔法
with bloodmagic.
史坦尼斯赎罪时  他们人呢
And when Stannis paid for his crime, where were they?
准备另找一位更有前途的主君
Already out looking for a leader with better prospects.
还有那个大胡子野人...
And that wildling fellow with the beard--
琼恩不是托蒙德  不是戴佛斯
Jon isn't Tormund. Jon isn't Davos,
不是红袍女  不是史坦尼斯
the Red Woman or Stannis for that matter.
琼恩就是琼恩
Jon is Jon.
她是我哥哥  他会护我安全  我相信他
He's my brother. He'll keep me safe. I trust him.
那他问你如何获得奔流城的消息时
Then why did you lie to him
你为什么不对他说实话呢
when he asked you how you learned about Riverrun?
新衣服啊
New dress?
我自己缝的  你喜欢吗
I made it myself. Do you like it?
当然  我喜欢那个狼
Yeah, it's-- I like the wolf bit.
很好  因为我给你做了这个
Good, because I made this for you.
照着以前父亲穿的样式
I made it like the one Father used to wear.
尽量按照记忆中的样子
As near as I can remember.
谢谢你  珊莎
Thank you, Sansa.
不客气
You're welcome.
我走后别把这里拆了
Don't knock it down while I'm gone.
我尽力
I'll do my best.
祝你好运
Good luck.
我们要关上门吗  总司令大人
Should we close the gate, Lord Commander?
我不是总司...
I'm not the Lord Comman--
是的  关上该死的门
yeah, ahem, close the bloody gate.
我们现在可以回家了  阿多
We can go home now, Hodor.
当然  也许算不上真正的家
Well, maybe not home home,
但好歹不是山洞
but somewhere that isn't a cave.
阿多
Hodor.
也不用再吃苔藓
Eat something that isn't moss.
我想吃鸡蛋  你喜欢怎么做的
I want an egg. How do you like 'em?
煮呢  还是用黄油煎呢
Boiled? Fried up with some butter?
阿多
Hodor.
再来点熏肉片和血肠
With a rasher of bacon and some blood sausage.
阿多
Hodor.
带上布兰快跑
Get Bran and run!
布兰  布兰  醒醒
Bran. Bran, wake up.
-布兰  -阿多  阿多
- Bran. - Hodor. Hodor.
布兰  醒醒
Bran, wake up.
-诸神保佑你在国王大道上平安  -别担心
- Gods keep you on the kingsroad. - Take it easy.
照顾自己
Watch yourself.
阿多
Hodor.
阿多  阿多
Hodor. Hodor.
来帮忙
Help me!
走
Go!
记住你是史塔克家的人
Remember that you are a Stark.
去了艾林谷要注意言行举止
Comport yourself with dignity at the Vale
别跟人打架
and try to stay out of fights.
是  父亲
Yes, Father.
如果躲不开  要打赢
But if you have to fight, win.
布兰  布兰  醒过来
Bran! Bran, wake up!
布兰  布兰  醒醒
Bran! Bran! Bran, wake up.
-布兰  醒醒  -阿多  阿多
- Bran! Bran, wake up! - Hodor. Hodor.
你必须醒过来
You have to wake up.
-我们需要阿多  -阿多  阿多
- We need Hodor. - Hodor. Hodor.
布兰  我们需要阿多
Bran, we need Hodor.
布兰  你必须醒来  我们需要阿多
Bran, you have to wake up. We need Hodor.
阿多  阿多
Hodor. Hodor.
布兰  我们都会死
Bran, we're all going to die!
布兰  醒醒
Bran, wake up!
我们都会死  布兰  布兰
We're all going to die! Bran! Bran!
布兰  你必须醒来  我们需要阿多
Bran, you have to wake up. We need Hodor.
阿多  阿多
Hodor. Hodor.
快控制阿多
Warg into Hodor now!
布兰  醒醒  我们需要阿多
Bran, wake up. We need Hodor.
我们需要阿多  快控制阿多  快
We need Hodor. Warg into Hodor now! Now!
听你朋友的话  布兰登
Listen to your friend, Brandon.
阿多  阿多
Hodor. Hodor.
-夏天  -跑
- Summer! - Go.
跑
Go!
时候到了
The time has come.
别管我
Leave me.
-你要干什么  -快跑
- What are you doing? - Go!
阿多  快点
Hodor, hurry!
阿多
Hodor!
堵住门
Hold the door!
-堵住门  -威里斯
- Hold the door! - Wylis!
怎么了
What's the matter?
-堵住门  -醒醒  儿子
- Hold the door! - Come on, son.
堵住门
Hold the door!
堵住门  堵住门
Hold the door! Hold the door!
堵住门
Hold the door!
堵住门  堵住门
Hold the door! Hold the door!
堵住门  堵门
Hold the door! Hold door!
堵门  堵住门
Hold door! Hold the door!
堵住门  堵门  堵门
Hold the door! Hold door! Hold door!
堵门  阿多
Hold door! Hodor!
阿多  阿多
Hodor! Hodor!
阿多
Hodor!
█
一大波正版授权“权力的游戏”周边向你靠近！
手机淘宝扫描左侧二维码
一起加入剧粉队伍～
搜索微信公众号
宅电社动漫 有福利哦
█
特别鸣谢人人影视